# 太漂亮了
Gorgeous
# 那叫一个地道
That is how it should be.
# 一磨这个香味
The fragrance bursts out after grinding
# 这面比这牛肉好吃
The noodles are going to taste better than the meat.
# 炙子炒面 大爷
Da Ye, we are making the fried noodles on the cast iron plate.
# 牛肉 牛外脊 顶刀切
Here is our beef short loin and we are slicing it against the grain
# 这个牛肉给它拍一下
Let’s pound it a bit
# 更容易入味了
For a better marination
# 而且它把肉的质地给它拍松了
It also tenderizes the meat
# 它在传热的时候
It prevents it from shrinking
# 它不会（缩）再回不来了
When it hits the heat
# 所以比较松 大爷说的太对了
So it stays loose (Da Ye is right)
# 而且肉质特别嫩
And tender
# 葱姜水来点
We need some ginger-spring onion water
# 黄酒 葱姜酒水
That is, ginger and spring onion soaked in water and Huangjiu rice wine
# 搁点盐 胡椒粉
Salt and pepper
# 搁点鲜味汁 这牛肉更加鲜
A bit of umami seasoning to enhance the taste.
# 再来点蚝油 正好
Some oyster sauce, perfect.
# 多了咸了 入味提鲜
Just enough to bring more umami, if you put too much it will get salty.
# 它有一定的黏度 包裹在一起
It also provides some stickiness.
# 食用小苏打 两克
A bit of baking soda, about 2 grams
# 搁苏打起嫩的
It further tenderizes the meat
# 非常嫩了 如果说再腌上半个小时更嫩
It is already very tender. If you marinate it for another 30 minutes, it will be more tender.
# 先给它上浆 来点香油 抓黏糊了
Give it a good mix with some sesame oil
# 葱姜酒水 多打点水没事 就这么让它往上抓
Then the garlic-spring onion water. It’s fine to add a bit more while you keep mixing it.
# 抓完了还能吃
The meat can absorb even more water.
# 再来点儿
Let’s add some more.
# 吃饱了再吃
When the water was absorbed by the meat.
# 蛋清少许
A little bit of egg white.
# 上了劲儿以后弄上淀粉
Once the meat becomes sticky, we will add the starch.
# 放点玉米淀粉 锁住水分
We are using corn starch to lock the moisture in the meat.
# 再给你封点油
Then we add some oil
# 封上油就润了
With oil, it will be moist.
# 切点辅料 洋葱别太少了
Chop other ingredients. The amount of onions shouldn't be too little.
# 胡萝卜
Carrots
# 这葱丝来点 您这配料可不少啊
Green onion jubilee. There are a lot of ingredients.
# 这个咱就来源于炙子烤肉
This dish was inspired by the cast iron BBQ meat.
# 先把孜然给它焙一下 指着这个出香味
Let’s roast the cumin first to extract the aroma.
# 小火慢慢焙 焙香了
Bake it on low heat
# 直接倒蒜臼子里
Pour it in the motar and grind
# 这就比机器打出来的香啊
This is better than using an electronic grinder.
# 看这一打直冒烟儿
Look at that “smoke”
# 一磨这个香味
The aroma bursts out once you start grinding.
# 熟芝麻
Cooked sesame
# 滑牛肉 锅必须得烧热了 已经冒烟了
Now let’s quickly fry the beef. The wok needs to be smoking hot.
# 涮锅
Coat the wok with some oil.
# 给倒回去
Pour this out
# 润锅 润锅很重要
Run Guo (completely coat the wok with oil).  It’s very important,
# 即便是原来的油也得加上凉油
We must put a little bit cold oil into the warm oil.
# 多搁点牛肉片吧 喜兴
Let’s cook more beef, it looks better.
# 先别动 一点都没粘
Don’t move, it won’t stick.
# 一抖落就开了 火候到了
See how it separates once you shake it? It’s cooked perfectly.
# 这么大牛肉块 肯定香
Large pieces tastes so much better.
# 大爷你看它这肉还真嫩
Look, Da Ye, the beef is really tender.
# 炙子 这是关键
The cast iron plate is the key to this dish
# 没炙子有这大铁板也行
Any metal plate will do
# 没铁板用砂锅也行
Or a clay pot
# 没砂锅咱就炒完了搁盘儿里也一样
If you don’t have any, then just fry it in your wok and plate it.
# 关小火了
Turn the heat down
# 放点油 烧的热热的 不热出不来香味
Let’s heat up the oil. You need hot oil to get the aroma out.
# 再来点香油 二合油可香啊
Mix it with some sesame oil.
# 洋葱 现加这些不够咱再加
Onions in. We have more if we need them.
# 先煸葱头
Spring onion
# 胡萝卜也可以先加上 真香
Now let’s put the carrots in. (smells good)
# 这时候牛肉搁进去
Now it’s time for the beef.
# 来点酱油 入一下味
Some soy sauce to bring up the flavor.
# 这个菜绝对好吃
It will be really good.
# 胡椒粉
Pepper powder.
# 为了口感 掐菜来点儿
Some bean sprouts for the texture.
# 拌完油以后蒸二十分钟的面 提前蒸的
We mixed the noodles with some oil and steamed them for 20 mins in advance.
# 千万别打盖儿 打盖儿就蒸呲了
Don’t put the lids on, otherwise the noodles may get soggy.
# 来点老抽
Some dark soy sauce.
# 市场买的切面
The noodles are freshly made.
# 在家都能做出酒店的味出来
You can replicate the restaurant tastes at home
# 您说这两条 这个面绝对好吃 干香
You are right, this is going to turn out to be so delicious.
# 它有肉啊 我好几天都没吃着肉了
Look at the beef. I haven’t eaten any meat for days.
# 还得加点 来点老抽
We need some more soy sauce.
# 不放盐
We don’t need any extra salt.
# 鲜味汁来一点 这颜色好啊
We also need a bit more umami sauce. Look at the color.
# 少来点香油
A bit of sesame oil.
# 孜然粒多来点
We need more cumin
# 孜然跟芝麻 刚才捶好了的
Cumin grinded with sesame
# 辣椒面 您看着面条 盖了帽儿了
Chili flakes in. Look at the noodles, how amazing is that!
# 整个都加进去吧 这才好吃呢
Just put them all in there for the flavor.
# 这面条
Look at this noodle.
# 赶紧照相赶紧照相
Quick, take a shot of this.
# 来着 关火关火
Here we go, off the heat.
# 太漂亮了这个
This is beautiful.
# 那叫一个地道
That’s how it’s supposed to be.
# 我可吃了 您吃 您给多提意见大爷
May I? Sure, give me some suggestions, Da Ye.
# 刚强 真香
Gang Qiang, delicious!
# 二伯 这面比这牛肉好吃
Er Bai, you know what, the noodles taste better than the beef.
# 炒面一定油要大
To fry the noodles properly, you will need enough oil.
# 而且它的孜然辣椒面加的好
And a perfect amount of cumin and chili flakes.
# 干香 牛肉这嫩
The beef is crispy, fragrant and tender.
# 这面这孜然辣椒面加的好
The cumin and chili flakes are really good in the noodle.
# 这是一大创举
It’s a good innovation.
# 大爷为什么今天戴着帽子
Why is Da Ye wearing a hat?
# 你知道什么意思吗
You know why?
# 我们俩用我们的行动来表扬你
This is to complement you.
# 你的产品接地气儿
The dish is also very down-to-earth.
# 真香 太好吃了
It is so delicious.
# 番茄酱和番茄沙司的区别
What’s difference between tomato sauce and ketchup?
# 区别大了
Quite a large difference.
# 因为番茄沙司是
Ketchup is
# 通过番茄酱进一步的进行调味
basically tomato sauce with some further seasoning.
# 形成一种调味品
It’s a type of seasoning sauce
# 你看我们在 M记 开封菜
See, in McDonalds or KFC
# 吃的薯条 或者一些干炸食品
The french fries, or other deep-fried food
# 大家蘸上番茄沙司吃 就很有味道
We dip with ketchup, tastes good.
# 但是我们做菜 用的番茄酱
But we usually use tomato sauce for cooking
# 我们用一般不用番茄沙司
We hardly use ketchup
# 我不知道他调的味道有什么变化
Because we do not know what extra seasoning is in the sauce.
# 所以番茄酱里面是没有味道的
There is no extra seasoning in the tomato sauce
# 该加盐加盐 该加糖加糖
So we can control the amount of salt, sugar
# 该加醋加醋
Or vinegar
# 不管是做大甜酸 小甜酸
When we make the sweet-sour dishes
# 包括果汁的一些菜肴
Or some dishes with fruits.
# 特别恰到好处
It is better to use tomato sauce.
# 所以这个番茄酱和番茄沙司的区别
So, the difference between the two
# 就是一个调好味了 一个没调好味
One is seasoned, one is not.
# 就自己在调制一些糖醋汁的话
So when you are making some sweet-sour sauce
# 或者有一些手法的话
Or some other cooking methods,
# 它适当的少量的加一些番茄酱
You can add some tomato sauce
# 他为了中和一下这颜色
It adds a bit of the color
# 但又不破坏味道
Without affecting the seasoning
# 后续的味道去自己加去
So that you can control the seasoning yourself.
# 行 下一个
OK next
# 还有
What’s next